# MIN THEIN TUN

### S Y S T E M A D M I N I S T R A T O R



+971-562435745

mintheintun@outlook.com

Al Rigga, Deira, Dubai, UAE

mintheinhtun.website

## PROFILE

I am a qualified and professional system administrator with over five years of experience in Network, Servers, and Cloud administration.

I am self-motivated, hardworking, and a disciplined person.

Team player with an eye for detail.

## SKILLS

- Windows Server Administration
- Linux Server Administration
- Cloud Computing (AWS, Azure & GCP)
- Cyber Security
- Network Administration
- Problem-Solving
- Computer Literacy
- Project Management Tools
- Strong Communication
- DevOps
- Virtualization

## EDUCATION

EXECUTIVE DIPLOMA IN SERVER ENGINEERING & SERCURITY HARDENING

Lincoln University College 2019 - 2020

EXECUTIVE DIPLOMA IN NETWORK & SERVER INFRASTRUCTURE

Lincoln University College 2018 - 2019

## EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

#### Hirokei Myanmar Systems

April 2023 - Present

- Managing and Administration the Cloud Servers.
- Build and deploy the CRM Systems on the Linux Cloud Server.
- Database Administration and Security Configuration for CRM Systems (MySQL, MariaDB, and PostgreSQL ...etc)
- Build and deploy the Odoo ERP Systems on the Linux Cloud Servers.
- HA-Proxy server configuration for website load Balancing and SSL Certificate termination.
- Creating the testing environments in On-prime Servers for the Development Team.
- VPN server installation and configuration to log in to the Cloud servers via secure IPSec Tunnel.
- Managing and Configuring the Local Hypervisor that installs VMware, Hyper-V, and Xen.
- VM creation, Storage Mounting, and Security Hardening for Local and Cloud Infrastructure.
- Daily monitoring with Zabbix and PRTG for the servers that running our customer's systems.
- Microsoft 365 Administration for Office user daily operation.
- Cloud environment administration for AWS, Azure, and GCP.
- Firewall Network filtering, Log File checking, and Prevention from abnormal cases for Office Network using Dell Sonicwall.
- Daily operation support for office users and customer sites.
- Daily working process details report to the Managing Director.

#### **BACHELOR OF HISTORY**

West Yangon University

2016 - 2020

## CERTIFICATES

#### **Fortinet Training Institute**

FORINET CERTIFIED FUNDAMENTALS IN CYBER SECURITY

FORINET CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE IN CYBER SECURITY

NETWORK SECURITY EXPERT-1

NETWORK SECURITY EXPERT-2

#### **Linux Lab Institute**

RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

#### **EnGenius**

ENGENIUS CERTIFIED NETWORK SPECIALIST ENGENIUS CERTIFIED NETWORK PROFESSIONAL

#### **AWS**

AWS CLOUD PARTITIONER ESSENTIALS

#### MYANMAR ROUTE TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED AZURE ADMINISTRATOR

LINUX ESSENTIALS

#### **KMD INSTITUTE**

NETWORK ENGINEERING PRACTICAL A+ ADVANCE

# SYSTEM & NETWORK ENGINEER [ASSISTANT MANAGER]

Jan 2023 - April 2023

**G** Bank

- Daily reporting to the Data Center Manager.
- Monitoring the banking infrastructures (Network, Storage, Servers, VMs, Firewall, and F5 Load Balancer)
- Create and configure the system resources when requested by the DBA
   Team and Core Team.
- Preparing documents for Vendor comparison, contracts, and other Government office letters.
- Drawing Infrastructure Design for the Banking Systems.
- Prepare for Data Center Migration to New Data Center.
- Configuration Firewall with HUB-Spoke method from Data Center to Braches of Bank.
- Configuration vCenter and Creating new VMs or Storage.
- Configuration Monitoring server for Core Banking Software and Mobile Banking Software.

Reference Person: Mr. Ahkar Swe Designation: Data Center Manager

Contact: [+959400516526]

# SYSTEM ENGINEER [ ASSISTANT SUPERVISOR ] AYA SOMPO INSURANCE

April 2019 - Jan 2023

- Co-leader for the System Team to manage and maintain the office infrastructure.
- Managed and administered the Windows servers that ran ADDS, WDS, and File Server.
- Manage and monitor all installed systems and network infrastructure.
- Install, configure, test, and maintain operating systems, application software, and system management tools.
- Proactively ensure the highest levels of systems and infrastructure availability.
- Monitor and test application performance for potential bottlenecks, identify possible solutions and work with developers to implement those fixes.
- · Maintain security, backup, and redundancy strategies.
- Participate in the design of information and operational support systems.
- Liaise with vendors and other IT personnel for problem resolution.
- Helpdesk support for daily operation processes.
- Provide 2nd and 3rd level support.
- Microsoft 365 Administration and Develop Power App Platform for Payment Process
- Deploy company websites and company internal software on the cloud environment.

#### **PROJECT ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Monitoring Servers Installation and Configuration for Banking Systems.
   (Zabbix, Splunk, PRTG, NetGain)
- VPN Server Installation for IPSec Tunneling. (OpenVPN, Outline VPN)
- New Head Quarter Setup Project (Network, Server, Storage, CCTV...etc.)
- New Branch Office Setup Project (Network, Server, Storage, CCTV...etc.)
- Exchange Mail Server Installation Project on On-Prime.
- Exchange Mail Server to Microsoft 365 Migration Project
- Data Center Migration from Old Data Center to New Data Center.
- Cloud Infrastructure Migration from the Singapore Region to the Thailand Region.